all right what's up guys welcome back to
another set and forget podcast you guys
already know this is episode three i
think that we are solo you guys already
know i'm starting my psychology series
on uh trading so you guys are not have a
psychology course i'm literally going to
be pointing it to you guys out for free
here on youtube spotify apple podcast
wherever it is that you guys are
listening to this video um so with that
being said this episode we're gonna
start the actual structure because if
you guys know the last two videos uh
first of all the last video that i did
which was the
the surfing analogy you guys loved it
like go look at the comments like it's
ridiculous it's probably i personally
think one of my best videos overall
whether it's educational podcast or just
anything that i have ever posted that
has probably been the most
video that makes not only the most sense
but that it could affect your journey
like it can really shift your journey in
180 degrees and put you in the right
direction if i would have heard what i
said in that video two years ago it
would have not took me as long to get to
where i am today
but like how i say not my friends say
everything happens for a reason it is
what it is it's just part of the journey
but that last video the amount of love
the amount of this interaction that i
got on that last videos was ridiculous
and i hope you guys are ready for what's
to come because now it's the actual
psychology series the last video was
kind of like a little introduction gem
to would expect for the next uh couple
of videos um with that being said this
is gonna be video number one official of
the psychology series and that's going
to be money mindset right
what do i mean by money mindset well
this is very crucial reason is because
let's be honest we're in the business of
money finances we're not out here
selling cars or we're not out here just
simply going to fish or in the gym we're
not in fitness we're in the industry of
finance right so if you go to the gym
you have to be in the right
physical to in order to you know lift
certain weights or be in certain
trainings if you're going to be in sales
you need to be good at communication or
persuasion or whatever you're doing
sells right to my point is that we're in
the finance space we're in the money
space so you need to have the right
money mindset so what do i mean by that
well
to a lot of people for example let's say
five thousand dollars is a lot of money
right and in the case of many 5 000
could be a lot that could pay many
expenses monthly or it could pay for a
vacation or any debt that one person may
have but there's also
what you want to do with your money
let's say you're making five thousand
dollars extra where do you want to live
luxury would you want to go to vacations
a lot of people out there have different
goals for example a lot of people like
luxuries whether it be cars jewelry
fancy restaurants big house vacation
home other people just rather travel so
they would rather be working remotely
from wherever they work so they can
literally go to the bahamas hawaii or
wherever it is that you want to go
travel and that's a different type of
luxury because you don't report to
anybody you're basically living at your
own terms you could clock into work work
whenever you want and then you do
whatever you want you don't have any
change and you watch it you just like
being independent doing whatever you
want however you want if you want but
let's be honest guys we're in the
financial industry same way how out
there let's say we were to go into the
fitness space and the normal in the
fitness space is running a mile right i
have no idea this is an example let's
say the normal in the fitness space is
running a mile if you run a mile you
can't be holy [__] yeah random number
like this is what we do here right let's
say you're going to go be a salesperson
at a car dealership and you know you
sell two cars a month you can't oh [__]
i sold two no like this is what you do
here you're here to sell cars and you
just move on it's into the trading just
because you made four five thousand
dollars you can't go crazy oh my god no
like bro you're in the financial
industry like there's trillions of
dollars being moved here on a daily
basis like you see just search it up how
much money is traded on a daily basis in
forks
at the beginning when i started trading
was like 6.3 trillion i think the market
cares if you take 5 10 20 000 no it's
not even a scratch so this leads me to
my point the majority of the people are
used to making a month let's say
anywhere from four to five thousand
dollars a month let's just call it five
thousand dollars flat right just for
example purposes this is good you're
living good you know you're paying your
bills you're being able to take out to
go eat little vacations here and there
you're you know but let's be honest it's
not enough to live the luxuries that you
want right so you come in with that same
energy saying all right if i were to
just make double if i were to make
instead of 5 000 a month if i could make
10 in the charts i'll be happy simply
because out of the money that i make
from work i can spend it and the other
five thousand dollars i can either save
it or live this luxury lifestyle that
you want
which is okay but i'm explaining to you
guys why this is crucial to your trading
due to the fact that when you come to
the charts with that energy let's say
you set a trade to have a take profit of
a one to four risk to reward at that one
at that one to four risk to reward your
profit target was fifteen thousand
dollars but simply because you're up on
the trade let's say a one to two risk to
reward and you're up those five thousand
dollars you're like oh my god what i'm
making a whole month i'm just up right
now boom you click close this is
probably one of the most crucial things
you could do to your trading because now
at this point
you're not taking trades logistically
based off of what the market is showing
you you are now taking and closing a
trade off of impulse emotion to the
dollar amount that you are entitled to
or stuck to or you just feel like it's a
lot so the money that you make a month
you're like alright cool i just doubled
that i close the trade keeps on going it
could have given you 15 000 and this is
the issue because since you're not used
to making
double the amount of money once you get
it you don't know how to handle it and
you blow it so let's say you actually
get that money in your possession you
would drive to your bank you're not used
to making this amount of money so once
you get it either you don't know how to
manage it or at that point you're
emotional and you either spend it
sporadically or you try to double it
triple it and that's where you lose all
the money and this is where i need you
guys to understand the money mindset
like five thousand dollars is not a lot
it might be a lot for one time two times
but you're not gonna be able to live a
certain lifestyle with five thousand
dollars a month let's be honest you can
get five thousand dollars anywhere in
this
forex industry with literally seven
hundred dollars you've got a leveled up
society and you can get funded a hundred
thousand dollars like do you know what
that is do you see the leverage that you
are getting
700 or 650 whatever the account is
versus 100k
your 5 000 has just turned into a
hundred k with simply a one to two to
risk to reward trade by just risking six
hundred fifty dollars like the leverage
that you have in this industry is a lot
different and this is where you guys
need to fall into the right money
mindset because if you just come into
this with a percentage based risk
everything changes you no longer need to
come into this space and be like all
right i am now going to come and make
ten thousand dollars a month i want to
make double what i make at my job no you
have a hundred thousand dollar account
manage it according to what that account
is i wanna make seven twelve fifteen
percent a month if you can make seven
ten percent on any account literally
just do the math on any account that you
want if you make 10 on a 10 000 account
you can make 10 on a million dollar
account i could have that account copied
on a different copy trader like if i
give you right now a 10k account and i'm
like bro just flip it and you turn it
from 10 to let's say 12 000 meaning you
just made twenty percent and i could
have that account connected to a copy
trader with a million dollar account you
just made 20 on the million dollar on
the million dollar account like yo look
you just made 200k oh my god i just made
200k no bro you just made 20 it's the
same thing that's where you guys need to
understand that is i percentage base
rate you need to completely eliminate
the factor of the dollar money it's the
same percentage different account size
and this is where i need you guys to
understand that it is just numbers on a
screen your goal here is to transfer
numbers from one screen to another
screen from the charts to your bank
account once you're in bank account you
do whatever you want with it and that's
what i'm going to be giving you guys
later on the money rule which is my 30
30 10 rule but i'll be explaining that
to you guys right so you guys need to
understand when you get the money from
one screen to the other screen you're
not good do not do not get the like
attachment to the money you need to come
to this with a percentage based risk and
this is the issue because you're
comparing you what you make at your job
with the charts no you're in the wrong
mindset this is you see how i how i
bring it back to it like you have the
mindset of a job of a hard worker which
is cool stay there leave that mind there
disconnect it once you clock out and
plug in your money mindset once you come
into the charts because everything
completely changes you can come in with
that same approach that you come in from
your job
two trading forks
and this can also basically be with the
people you surround yourself whether it
be at work outside of work or just
people you surround yourself with in
general let's say you're trading because
this happened to me so there's like a
personal experience that i'm you know
sharing with you guys i remember that um
when i was sitting with some old school
friends
like one of my first times flipping an
account i think i had taken like maybe
five thousand to like i don't know like
eight nine thousand right and i was
showing them like look bro i just made
3k in like a day and a half they're like
bro dude that's so much money bro close
it you're crazy close it i'm just like
why like it's not done like i still got
so much more bro you're crazy dude you
don't want to lose all that money just
you know close with it run it you got
lucky basically calling you you know
that it was out of luck so whatever [__]
i closed the trade they're right i come
back to the screen and i look at the
charts i could have made 10 15 000 off
the trade at that point i'm not only mad
at myself like i can't be mad at that
person because you know i went and i
clicked the button but i got mad at
myself because i just listened to
somebody else and that's when i realized
who you surround yourself with is who
you're going to end up being so you got
to be around the right people but this
would be into like another episode that
i get into
and how to get into those spaces so
the being surrounded with the wrong
people will affect your training because
to them that's a lot of money i was up
three thousand four thousand in profit
and i'm like bro this is cool like i was
already entering that phase like that
like that mindset where i was just
getting numb to it i'm like bro this is
really not that much like there's a lot
more that i can make off of this so
having that person around you makes you
kind of go back to that different
mindset to that work mindset to that
poor mindset where it's like damn that
is a doubt like that is a lot of money
that you could have just made from the
money close it right away that's very
very very crucial to your decision
making when it comes to trading the
charge do you want to make sure when it
comes to certain things like this and
you're plugged in in this certain
mindset don't don't show anybody else
just stay in your own life stay stay in
your lane do your thing and focus on
what so i'm gonna give you guys my 30 30
30 10 rule that i use not only for like
my finances but for my whole entire life
as a whole and this is 10x to me
everybody around me uses it and it's
it's honestly ridiculous right so 30 30
30 10 rule write this down tattoo it put
on your wall do whatever you got to do
right so obviously a hundred percent of
your income you can't just splurge it
you can't just go out there and spend it
you can't just invest at all you can't
just save it all you have to know how to
properly manage money so this is a very
basic and very powerful way of managing
your money 100 of your income you
divided them for 30 30 30 10. 30 of your
income needs to go to your residual
expenses whether it's your
mortgage your car payments insurance
food whatever you have residual every
single month without you leaving your
front door you know you got to pay that
has to be 30 of your income the other
thirty percent of your income you save
you gotta have you gotta be liquid you
gotta have someone in the bank account
just in case for a rainy day because you
know [__] happens [__] around another
kobe comes by we have no idea you know
who knows with bite and being [__]
whatever right so then third has to be
30 of your income you have to invest you
have to invest this money whether it's
in a parked asset or something that
something that goes up in value whether
it's a crypto
stock um yourself books get funded like
you need to invest money because if you
throw it into the savings you're gonna
either just spending it or it's just not
doing you any good you need to have
other sources of income you need to
multiply your money because you can make
all the money but even at multiplying it
you're not doing anything you're
literally cutting yourself short by half
you're literally just cutting your
income in half because you're not doing
anything with it so mandatory invest it
in something that will make you better
it will bring your return in the future
and then 10 is what you splurge you go
out to you know the club or
party or whatever you want to do with
your money i personally try to not even
have this i personally try to add this
into the investment as much as i can
simply because i just want to compound
as much money as i make right now since
i'm young and just keep it going
throughout the years and then eventually
start spending so i want you guys to
listen to this analogy really fast
because i definitely think this is my
top three analogies when it comes to
comparing finances to just any regular
life analogy right so society sets you
up for failure what do i mean by that
let's say right now you get a corporate
job for the next 15 20 years after you
retire or before you retire they're
gonna pay you a salary and that salary
is not going to go up it's that's just
what you get paid if anything after five
ten years they're gonna raise it just
very slightly right what does that do is
you're just capped there's no room for
you to grow you're just stuck within
that same amount you're just used to
that amount you're not you don't know
how to manage anything else other than
what you are currently making which is
your standard you know if you mess up
next one they're going to get the same
amount and that's your window for you to
manage
let's say right now we're hitting the
gym for 15 20 years and then i just
always whenever you go hit the bench
press you only put a 20 pound so for 15
20 years you're hitting a 20 pound on
the bench press literally capping you to
the potential of your growth of your
strength of whatever as big as you can
get but this here comes the issue let's
say one day i decide to add a 10 to the
bench press you're not going to know how
to manage it because you're used to
making
you're not going to know how to manage
it because you're used to just lifting
the 20 pounds so the moment that i add
the 10 pound you get become unstable and
you don't know how to manage it same
exact thing happens when it comes to the
base salary when people are getting paid
a certain amount of money for 15 20
years when they start seeing all these
numbers on the screen on forex it kind
of throws them off because they're not
used to managing this amount of money
and that's where emotions greed fear and
just this whole entire
issue occurs because they have been
using the wrong mindset where they have
been coming from a corporate job and
they're getting now introduced to this
crazy world that it's unlimited
opportunities and it throws off their
imbalance so keep that in mind if you're
currently being capped just know that if
they ever put another dumbbell on you
you got to be prepared for what's to
come so i hope you guys enjoyed this
video this is just video number one of
what to expect in the psychology series
you guys already know
we got an app coming out app is probably
coming out in two to three weeks there's
gonna be so many gems coming out in
there if you guys want to see more
educational stuff make sure to join my
free telegram in the link below um you
guys are if you guys want to get funded
level of society's only place to do it
you guys want to be part of the level up
crew and um with that being said
appreciate you guys watching the video
all the way to the end and i'll see you
guys in the next episode